Matthew R. Miller

MatthewMillerDesign@gmail.com (503) 896-9545

SUMMARY

After receiving my bachelor's degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering, I have been working with the United States Navy on the Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation of new torpedo based systems. I have received awards for being part of multi-national research and readiment projects. This diversity has prepared me to transition my field of research to robotics and continue working on academic teams.

EXPERIENCE

Electronics Engineer

Naval Undersea Warfare Center Keyport Division Keyport, WA

Fall 2020-Present

Lead Electrical Engineer for the Special Projects rapid R&D group and have assisted in building, deploying, retrieving, and data collection used to increased the knowledge and readiment needed by the US Fleet and the Fleet of sister countries. This has allowed me to work on multiple configurations of US Navy Test Vehicles, giving me insight to the development, prototyping, and deployment of MIL-Spec production level electronics and cables.

Software Developer

Underwater Audio Corvallis, OR

Spring 2018- Spring 2020

Developed, tested, and sourced parts for waterproof Android and Apple audio devices, as well as developed any accompanying software the company required. My skills developed from this position are developing hardware and software, sourcing parts, working successfully in a small team, creating devices from the prototype stage to final product, and front to back-end database and server management.

Assistant-Manager

Multnomah Falls Lodge Bridal Veil, OR

Spring 2013- Fall 2016

The majority of the time there was spent managing, and working with, the employees of three food stands. Skills developed from this position are time management, customer service, handling money, and large scale supply management.

Manage Firewood Sales

Gary Miller LLC Corbett,OR

Fall 2009-Present

Managed all aspects of the firewood production, sales, and delivery. My skills developed from this position are managing employees, paying wages, delivering product, sales, and overall problem solving for day to day operations.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Experience with circuit deign, testing, evaluation, and production

Member of underwater ROV and UUV team

Experience in digital logic design

Experience with micro-controller deign and utilization

Experience using: Python, Java, VHDL, C, C++, JavaScript, MATLAB, LATEX and more

Experience building and maintaining databases and servers

Taught NXT programming and building to a Boy Scout troop

EDUCATION

Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR Bachelor of Science, Electrical and Computer Engineering, Spring 2020 Minor, Computer Science, Spring 2020

Mt Hood Community College, Gresham, OR Mathematics, Fall 2014-2015

Corbett High School, Corbett, OR Honors Student, STEM School, May 2015

HONORS/ACHIVEMENTS

Eagle Scout
Community Volunteer
AP Scholar
Corbett GSA Member

Winner of the 2021 Commanding Officer's Award for Excellence